<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Movie Rankings</title>
<link>http://ianranksmovies.netlify.app/blog.html</link>
<atom:link href="http://ianranksmovies.netlify.app/blog.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.2.269</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 08:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>The Sight and Sound 2012 Data Set</title>
  <dc:creator>Ian McDonald</dc:creator>
  <link>http://ianranksmovies.netlify.app/posts/The Sight and Sound 2012 Dataset/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="the-sight-and-sound-2012-poll-dataset" class="level1">
<h1>The Sight and Sound 2012 Poll Dataset</h1>
<p>On December 1, Sight and Sound published the rollup of its 2022 100 Best Movies of All Time, and the reaction has calmed since then. The results are entertaining, the ballot counting process not so much. We know that the new Critics Poll best movie of all time is the Belgian 1975 film Jeanne Dielman etc. etc. We don’t yet know if the result represents a groundswell of support from new voters.</p>
<p>But we do have all of the ballots from the 2012 poll, and Sight and Sound says the individual ballots will be available online in January. The poll is a wonder because of individual ballots. Sight and Sound reveals as much in their T* feed which previews some selected ballots. The meaning of the aggregated lists is hard to interpret, but the variety of the individual lists spreads over every imaginable taste and movie pedagogy. You don’t just get different opinions. You get every strategy and level of engagement in a survey like this one, spurred by the poll’s reputation and its infrequency.</p>
<p>So how does it work? In 2012, Sight and Sound received returned ballots from 846 respondents to the critics poll, and 359 in its separate directors poll. One could combine them, but the critics poll receives the most attention.</p>
<p>Respondents are asked only to list ten movies, unranked. They can list any movie, a power that is freely exercised. The survey results simply count the occurrence of each movie on individual ballots. That’s it. The count is published alongside the ballots, though we haven’t seen the counts online.</p>
<p>What do individuals imagine a “greatest movie” signifies? Maybe something other than a “favorite”, maybe leaning toward ideas about importance or contribution to cinema as an art form. Maybe its a strategic spin on the post-poll buzz, or maybe an individual statement about unheralded movies that becomes public, since its not a secret ballot. Maybe its an endorsement of a type of movie, or a type of movie canon, that could be old or new.</p>
<p>Leave aside the Some people in the world care about preference aggregation, and if the Sight and Sound poll was worth the bother, they would have questions. Should we weight each movie equally on an individual ballot? Should every respondent be weighted equally? Should the choice set somehow be constrained by reputability? Why, in 2012, did Martin Scorsese and Quentin Tarantino get to list 12 movies instead of just 10?</p>
<p>The survey doesn’t need this kind of complexity. It only demands that we relax when the list shuffles around a bit, as it did from 2012 to 2022. As I have pointed out elsewhere, before we sweat the rise of Jeanne Dielman on the survey, we need to remember a few things about the 2012 surveys:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>The critics poll included 846 ballots, that chose 2019 individual movies. In a sense, we get 8460[] selections, spread over 2019 movies.</p></li>
<li><p>Of those 2019 films, 1125 of them were chosen by exactly one person.</p></li>
<li><p>The #1 film in 2012 was Vertigo because no other film exceed its 191 votes. Out of 846 ballots cast. That’s 22.6% that included Vertigo in the top ten. This means 77.4% of the ballot couldn’t find a place for the #1 movie in the top 10.</p></li>
</ul>
<p>Consider this list from <a href="https://www2.bfi.org.uk/films-tv-people/sightandsoundpoll2012/voter/150">archivist Robert Haller</a> in the 2012 critics poll who chose Vertigo and five other films chosen by nobody else:</p>
<p><img src="http://ianranksmovies.netlify.app/heller.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>A co-vote is the number of other ballots that contain the particular movie. We know that a voter for Vertigo has 190 co-votes, but notice the five films at the bottom. All great, all important, but only appearing once for a single voter.</p>
<p>This kind of table is a simplified version of network analysis, and when the 2022 data appears, we should learn how voters combine films, and how certain ballots and certain voters form clusters. For now, I can look at Mr.&nbsp;Heller’s list and see all kinds of movies that provoke my interest.</p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>data explainers</category>
  <guid>http://ianranksmovies.netlify.app/posts/The Sight and Sound 2012 Dataset/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="http://ianranksmovies.netlify.app/heller.png" medium="image" type="image/png" height="118" width="144"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Movie Rankings: Sight and Sound Poll Data, Tables, Figures, and More</title>
  <link>http://ianranksmovies.netlify.app/posts/welcome/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Find the <em>Sight and Sound</em> 2022 rankings <a href="https://www.bfi.org.uk/sight-and-sound/greatest-films-all-time">here: https://www.bfi.org.uk/sight-and-sound/greatest-films-all-time</a>:</p>
<p>Movie ranking connoisseurs know about <em>Sight and Sound</em> magazine and its 100 Greatest Films of All time lists for 2022, released on Dec.&nbsp;1.&nbsp;<em>Sight and Sound</em> is the flagship publication of the British Film Institute (BFI). &nbsp; The lists are compiled from its decennial survey of film critics and directors.</p>
<p>Five days later the discussion stays hot, and you may wonder: what does a greatest films survey like this reveal, should we care, and what makes the <em>Sight and Sound</em> lists special?</p>
<p>This year’s critics poll was notable because Chantal Akerman’s 1975 film <em>Jeanne Dielman, 23 quai du Commerce, 1080 Bruxelles</em> was the #1 ranked film, rising from 36<sup>th</sup>. In addition, eight of 2012’s top 20 were replaced.&nbsp; If you prefer, 12 of the 2012 top 20 were left standing, as were three of 2012’s top four.</p>
<p>The <em>Sight and Sound</em> poll isn’t the usual “best of the year” list, although the BFI produces many of those lists too. It’s infrequent, and the list comes from a survey, not a smoke filled room. This year it included 1639 critics and [lots of] directors, and it appears just once a decade. (I’m focusing on the critics poll here.)&nbsp; &nbsp;</p>
<p>The “all time” conceit, and the survey’s infrequency, promises some immutability.&nbsp;Consider the US News college rankings. When Cal Tech moves from 17<sup>th</sup> to 1<sup>st</sup> in one year, you wonder how could a credible survey have missed the mark last year, when you decided to forego Cal Tech in your college plans?. So how can you trust the new results?&nbsp; Can you realistically claim that <em>Godfather Part II</em> was the “31<sup>st</sup> greatest movie of all time” in 2012, and then drops off the list entirely in 2022?&nbsp;<img src="http://ianranksmovies.netlify.app/img/top_10_2012.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>But ten years is a long time. Roughly 1/4 of the movies from 2012’s Top 100 critics’ list fell out of it.&nbsp; Which means 3/4’s of the top 100 endured. By and large, the old canon was reasonably well protected in the 2022 poll, which you would never know from the online conversation. <em>The Godfather Part I</em> (1972), as canonical as it gets, actually rose into the top 20.&nbsp;We should expect change because some important movies are relatively new, others may be newly recognized as great, and sometimes the respondent pool changes. When fewer than 1/4 of the critics poll is comprised of women, as in 2012, the surveyors ought to fix it.</p>
<p>The crude aggregation process is a bigger concern, and an inherent one. The balloting process is built for simplicity and freedom for respondents. And freedom abounds. There are no fixed lists or fixed choices. Voters are simply asked to simply identify the “top 10 greatest movies of all time”, unranked. I may choose to include <em>Vertigo</em>, or I may include <em>Citizen Kane</em>, or both, or neither.&nbsp; I could vote for <em>Battlefield Earth</em>, or<em>The Door.</em> Some critics included a Tex Avery Warner Brothers cartoon.</p>
<p>When you ask opinionated, trained movie hounds about the greatest movie of all time, you get opinionated and idiosyncratic choices.&nbsp; You don’t get a real consensus. &nbsp;</p>
<p>The BFI generously posts individual ballots (universally available for 2022 in January, I’m told). In 2012 they provided a bit of demographic information about respondents (self-declared gender and nationality). In 2022, we can also break out the new voters from the old ones. &nbsp;</p>
<p>I scraped the BFI website and created a dataset with all the voters and all the ballot choices.&nbsp; Here’s what struck me looking at support for <em>Vertigo</em> and <em>Citizen Kane</em> for 2012, and the 846 critics ballots:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>Only 191 (22.6%) ballots included the eventual #1 choice, <em>Vertigo</em>, on their lists.&nbsp; That matters because 77.4% did not include the #1 movie (<em>Vertigo</em>) anywhere on their top 10 lists.</p></li>
<li><p>It’s not just that 77.4% didn’t think it was #1.&nbsp; The large majority didn’t even think <em>Vertigo</em> was in the top 10.&nbsp;</p></li>
<li><p>Only 157 ballots (18.6%) included <em>Citizen Kane,</em> ultimately the 2<sup>nd</sup> highest ranked film. &nbsp;</p></li>
<li><p>Only 299 respondents included either <em>Citizen Kane</em> or <em>Vertigo.</em></p></li>
<li><p>A majority of 547 (64.7%) included <em>neither</em> one. Again, the large majority (almost 2/3) didn’t say “Citizen Kane nor Vertigo weren’t #1”.&nbsp; The large majority said “neither of these is in my top 10!”</p></li>
</ul>
<p>Can you imagine a ballot for the American League MVP where 2/3 of the voters thought that neither Aaron Judge nor Shohei Ohtani was in the top 10?</p>
<p>And yet, the aggregation mechanism gave us Vertigo as #1 in 2012, and Citizen Kane every decade before that since the poll began in 1952. The poll simply counts the occurrences of each movie on all the ballots, and the #1 movie is simply the one that appears most often.&nbsp;</p>
<p>The support for all of the movies is spread very thin. In my count, 2,020 individual movies chosen by someone in the 2012 critics poll.&nbsp;Of these, 1,112 were chosen once by just one person. &nbsp;</p>
<p>Critics should also know:</p>
<ul>
<li><p>The bottom of each list in the 50-100 range includes a lot of ties, which are artifacts of low scores.&nbsp; We don’t know the tabulations yet, but 2022’s lowest ranked movie that isn’t in a tie is <em>Touki Bouki</em> in 66<sup>th</sup> place.&nbsp; The movies in places 67-100 are ranked in some kind of tie, and the bottom has a six way tie for 95<sup>th</sup> place. &nbsp;</p></li>
<li><p>In 2012, the bottom 9 movies were tied for 93<sup>rd</sup> place.&nbsp; Each of these movies got 17 votes, or 2% each.&nbsp; Remember, there are 10 votes per respondent, so there are 8460 different places a movie could appear.</p></li>
<li><p>A movie I love, <em>Sátántangó</em>, dropped from 38<sup>th</sup> place to a six way tie for 78<sup>th</sup>.&nbsp; The size of that drop doesn’t matter.&nbsp; <em>Sátántangó</em> probably received at least as many votes as it did in 2012 (34 wise souls).&nbsp; A handful of additional votes would make it 38<sup>th</sup> yet again. That kind of movement is a bit less likely among the top 20 but, below that, these rankings are volatile.&nbsp;</p></li>
</ul>
<p>In short, the support for all of these movies, at the top, in the middle, at the bottom, is very thin. A few votes can change a movie’s ranking dramatically. No movie gets anything near the support of a majority of voters. &nbsp;</p>
<p>Does this diversity of thought, and the casual aggregation, mean the poll is unworthy of the attention it gets?&nbsp; Absolutely not.&nbsp; The intellectual diversity gives the poll its credibility and utility.&nbsp; Everyone knows that a poll like this is an assessment, totally subjective, totally expressive.&nbsp; The individual’s greatest movie list of an any movie lover is a gift:&nbsp; they are saying, “pay attention to these, and if you do, you will learn something essential about the art.” It creates vulnerability.</p>
<p>I’m learning more about great cinema all the time but the 14 minute <em>Meshes of the Afternoon</em>, an experimental film from 1943 made for US$275, escaped my attention.&nbsp; It’s now 16<sup>th</sup> on the 2022 critics list.&nbsp; In 2012, <em>Meshes</em> received only 16 critics’ votes out of 846.&nbsp; So now I know about <em>Meshes in the Afternoon</em> and I can’t wait to see it.&nbsp; I saw <em>Jeanne Dielman</em> a while ago and I’ll never forget the experience.</p>
<p>Instead, we should recognize that the “Greatest Movie of All Time” is a tease, a conversation starter, and changes in the list are hints, not quantified cultural milestones.&nbsp;The exercise is a way for everyone who loves movies to say more about what they mean and why they love them. I think that’s the BFI’s intent, and if they have won a war for eyeballs this weekend, more power to them.</p>




<div class="quarto-listing quarto-listing-container-default" id="listing-listing">
<div class="list quarto-listing-default">

</div>
<div class="listing-no-matching d-none">
No matching items
</div>
</div> ]]></description>
  <guid>http://ianranksmovies.netlify.app/posts/welcome/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2022 08:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="http://ianranksmovies.netlify.app/img/top_10_2012.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
